In this video, I'd like to
这个视频，我想(字幕翻译：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
start talking about a second
开始谈论第二
type of unsupervised learning problem
类型的无监督学习问题
called dimensionality reduction.
称为降维。
There are a couple of different
有几个不同的
reasons why one might
的原因使你可能
want to do dimensionality reduction.
想要做降维。
One is data compression, and as
一是数据压缩，
we'll see later, a few videos
后面我们会看到，一些视频
later, data compression not only
后，数据压缩不仅
allows us to compress the
允许我们压缩
data and have it therefore
数据，因此
use up less computer memory
使用较少的计算机内存
or disk space, but it will
或磁盘空间，但它
also allow us to speed up our learning algorithms.
也让我们加快我们的学习算法。
But first, let's start by
但首先，让我们开始
talking about what is dimensionality reduction.
谈论降维是什么。
As a motivating example, let's say
作为一种生动的例子，让我们说
that we've collected a data set
我们收集的数据集
with many, many, many features,
带许多，许多，许多特征，
and I've plotted just two of them here.
我绘制两个在这里。
And let's say that unknown to
和假设未知
us two of the
我们两个的
features were actually the length
特征实际上是长度
of something in centimeters, and
用厘米表示
a different feature, x2, is
的不同特征，X2，是
the length of the same thing in inches.
用英寸的同一物体的长度。
So, this gives us a highly
所以，这给了我们高度
redundant representation and maybe
冗余表示，也许
instead of having two separate features x1
不是两个分开的特征x1
then x2,
和X2，
both of which basically measure the
这两个基本的长度度量，
length, maybe what we
也许我们
want to do is reduce the
想要做的是减少
data to one-dimensional and
数据到一维
just have one number measuring this length.
只有一个数测量这个长度。
In case this example seems a
这个例子似乎
bit contrived, this centimeter and
有点做作，这里厘米
inches example is actually not that
英寸的例子实际上不是那么
unrealistic, and not that different
不切实际的，两者并没有什么不同
from things that I see happening in industry.
从这件事情我看到的东西发生在工业上的事。
If you have hundreds
如果你有几百个
or thousands of features, it is
或成千上万的特点，它是
often this easy to
它这往往容易
lose track of exactly what features you have.
失去你需要的特征。
And sometimes may have
有时可能有
a few different engineering teams, maybe
几个不同的工程团队，也许
one engineering team gives you
一个工程队给你
two hundred features, a second
二百个特征，第二
engineering team gives you another
工程队给你另外
three hundred features, and a
三百个的特征，
third engineering team gives you five
第三工程队给你
hundred features so you have
五百个特征
a thousand features all together,
一千多个特征都在一起，
and it actually becomes hard to
它实际上会变得非常困难
keep track of you know, exactly which features
去跟踪你知道的那些特征
you got from which team, and
你从那些工程队得到的。
it's actually not that want to have highly redundant features like these.
其实不想有高度冗余的特征一样。
And so if the
所以如果，
length in centimeters were rounded
厘米的长度被舍入到
off to the nearest centimeter and
最接近的厘米和
lengthened inches was rounded off to the nearest inch.
英寸加长舍入到最近的英寸。
Then, that's why these examples
这就是为什么这些例子
don't lie perfectly on a
不在于完美地结合在一条
straight line, because of, you know, round-off
直线，因为，你知道，
error to the nearest centimeter or the nearest inch.
舍入误差在最近厘米或最近的英寸。
And if we can reduce
如果我们可以减少
the data to one dimension
数据到一维
instead of two dimensions, that reduces the redundancy.
取代二维，减少冗余。
For a different example, again maybe when there seems fairly less contrives.
一个不同的例子，又或许当似乎相当少的设计。
For may years I've
多年我
been working with autonomous helicopter pilots.
一直在研究直升飞机自动驾驶。
Or I've been working with pilots that fly helicopters.
我一直与直升机飞行员一起。
And so.
诸如此类。
If you were to measure--if you
如果你想测量——如果你
were to, you know, do a survey
想做，你知道，做一个调查
or do a test of these different
或做这些不同飞行员的测试
pilots--you might have one
——你可能有一个
feature, x1, which is maybe
特征，X1，这也许是
the skill of these
他们的技能
helicopter pilots, and maybe
（直升机飞行员），也许
"x2" could be the pilot enjoyment.
“X2”可能是飞行员的爱好。
That is, you know, how
这是表示
much they enjoy flying, and maybe
他们是否喜欢飞行，也许
these two features will be highly correlated. And
这两个特征将高度相关。
what you really care about might
你真正关心的可能
be this sort of
是这样的
this sort of, this direction, a different feature that really
类别，方向，不同的特征，决定
measures pilot aptitude.
飞行员的能力。
And I'm making up the name
和我的名字命名
aptitude of course, but again, if
资质的课程，但是，如果
you highly correlated features, maybe
你高度相关的特征，也许
you really want to reduce the dimension.
你真需要降低维数。
So, let me say a
所以，让我说
little bit more about what it
点什么
really means to reduce the
真的意味着减少
dimension of the data from
数据的维度，从
2 dimensions down from 2D
从2维（2D）
to 1 dimensional or to 1D.
到1维（1D）。
Let me color in
让我把
these examples by using different colors.
这些样本通过使用不同的颜色标注。
And in this case
在这种情况下，
by reducing the dimension what
的降维是什么。
I mean is that I would
我的意思是，我会
like to find maybe this
想找到这也许
line, this, you know, direction on
线，方向等你知道的东西
which most of the data seems
其中的绝大部分数据似乎
to lie and project all
在项目的所有
the data onto that line which
数据上的线
is true, and by doing
是真实的，并通过实践的。
so, what I can do
所以，我能做的
is just measure the
只是测量
position of each of the examples on that line.
每个样本在线上的位置。
And what I can do is come
我能做的就是
up with a new feature, z1,
建立新的特征，Z1，
and to specify the position
和在线上指定的位置
on the line I need only
就行，我只需要
one number, so it says
一个数，所以说
z1 is a new feature
Z1是一个新的特征
that specifies the location of
指定位置
each of those points on this green line.
这些点在这个绿色的线。
And what this means, is
这意味着什么，是
that where as previously if i
以前如果我
had an example x1, maybe
有个样本X1，也许
this was my first example, x1.
这是我的第一个例子，X1。
So in order to
为了
represent x1 originally x1.
代表X1原先的x1。
I needed a two dimensional number,
我需要一个二维数，
or a two dimensional feature vector.
或一个二维特征向量。
Instead now I can represent
现在我可以代表
z1. I could
z1。我可以
use just z1 to represent my first
用Z1代表我的第一个
example, and that's going to be a real number.
样本，这将是一个实数。
And similarly x2 you know, if x2
同样X2你知道，如果x2
is my second example there,
是我的第二个样本，
then previously, whereas this required
然后以前，而这需要
two numbers to represent if I
两个数字来表示如果我
instead compute the projection
代替计算投影
of that black cross
那黑色的十字架
onto the line.
到线。
And now I only need one
，现在我只需要一个
real number which is
实数
z2 to represent the
Z2代表
location of this point
点的位置
z2 on the line.
Z2就行了。
And so on through my M examples.
我的M个样本也一样。
So, just to summarize, if
所以，只是总结，如果
we allow ourselves to approximate
我们允许自己近似
the original data set by
设置由原始数据
projecting all of my
将我所有的
original examples onto this green
原始的例子在这绿色
line over here, then I
线在这里，然后我
need only one number, I
只需要一个数，我
need only real number to
只需要实数
specify the position of
指定位置
a point on the line,
就行了一点，
and so what I can
所以我可以
do is therefore use just
这么做，只使用
one number to represent the
一个数表示
location of each of
每一个
my training examples after they've been projected onto that green line.
我的训练例子的位置的，他们被投射到绿色线。
So this is an approximation to
这是一个近似
the original training self because
原先训练自己因为
I have projected all of my training examples onto a line.
我投射我所有的训练样本上的线。
But
但
now, I need to keep around
现在，我需要保持
only one number for each of my examples.
为我的每个实例设置唯一的数字。
And so this halves the memory
所以这两半的记忆
requirement, or a space requirement,
的要求，或空间的要求，
or what have you, for how to store my data.
或者你有什么，如何存储我的数据。
And perhaps more interestingly, more
也许更有趣的是，更多的
importantly, what we'll see
更重要的是，我们会今后看到什么
later, in the later
在以后的
video as well is that this
视频也是这样
will allow us to make
会使我们
our learning algorithms run more quickly as well.
我们的学习算法，跑得更快。
And that is actually,
实际上是，
perhaps, even the more interesting
也许，甚至更有趣
application of this data compression
应用这种数据压缩
rather than reducing the memory
而不是降低内存
or disk space requirement for storing the data.
或磁盘空间用于存储数据的要求。
On the previous slide we
上一个幻灯片我们
showed an example of reducing
显示的一个例子是减少
data from 2D to 1D.
数据维度从2D到1D。
On this slide, I'm going
在此幻灯片，我会
to show another example of reducing
显示另一个减少
data from three dimensional 3D to two dimensional 2D.
数据从三维到二维。
By the way, in the more typical
顺便说一句，在更典型的
example of dimensionality reduction
降维的例子
we might have a thousand dimensional
我们可能有一千维
data or 1000D data that
数据或数据，
we might want to reduce to
我们可能要减少
let's say a hundred dimensional or
到我们说的一百维，
100D, but because of
（100D），而是因为
the limitations of what I can plot on the slide.
画图的局限性，我可以在幻灯片里画出来。
I'm going to use examples of 3D to 2D, or 2D to 1D.
我要使用三维到二维的例子，或二维到一维。
So, let's have a data set like that shown here.
在这里。我们有一个数据集显示的一样，
And so, I would have a set of examples
我会有一系列的样本
x(i) which are points
X（i）---
in r3. So, I have three dimension examples.
R3。所以，我有三维的例子。
I know it might be a little
我知道这可能是一个小
bit hard to see this on the slide,
位置很难在这幻灯片里看到，
but I'll show a 3D point
不过我会显示一个三维点
cloud in a little bit.
像云那样一点点。
And it might be hard to see
它可能是很难在这里看清楚，
here, but all of this
但是所有
data maybe lies roughly on
的数据大致
the plane, like so.
平铺在一个平面，像这样。
And so what we can do
所以我们能做的就是
with dimensionality reduction, is take
降维，是把
all of this data and
所有数据，
project the data down onto
投影到
a two dimensional plane.
一个二维平面。
So, here what I've done is,
所以，在这里我所做的是，
I've taken all the data and I've
我已经把所有的数据和我
projected all of the data,
将所有的数据，
so that it all lies on the plane.
投影在平面上。
Now, finally, in order to
现在，最后，为了
specify the location of a
指定一个位置
point within a plane, we need two numbers, right?
点在一个平面，我们需要两个数字，对吗？
We need to, maybe, specify the
我们需要，也许，指定
location of a point along
的一个点的沿着轴位置
this axis, and then also
这个轴，然后还
specify it's location along that axis.
指定它在轴上的位置。
So, we need two numbers, maybe called
所以，我们需要两个数，或者说
z1 and z2 to specify
指定Z1和Z2
the location of a point within a plane.
的平面内的点的位置。
And so, what that means,
所以，这意味着什么，
is that we can now represent
是我们现在可以把
each example, each training example,
每一个样本，每个训练样本，
using two numbers that
使用两个数字来代表，
I've drawn here, z1, and z2.
我已经在这里，Z1和Z2。
So, our data can be represented
因此，我们的数据可以表示为
using vector z which are in r2.
使用向量Z是R2的子集
And these subscript, z subscript
这些下标，
1, z subscript 2, what
z下标1，Z下标2，
I just mean by that is that my
我的意思是，我
vectors here, z, you know, are two
向量Z，在这里，你知道，是个
dimensional vectors, z1, z2.
二维向量，Z1，Z2。
And so if I have some
所以如果我有一些
particular examples, z(i), or
的具体样本，Z（i），或
that's the two dimensional vector, z(i)1,
是一个二维向量，Z（i）1，
z(i)2.
Z（i）2。
And on the previous slide when
在上一个幻灯片中，
I was reducing data to one
我是减少数据的一个
dimensional data then I
维数据然后我
had only z1, right?
只有Z1，对吗？
And that is what a z1 subscript 1
这就是Z1下标1
on the previous slide was,
在上一个幻灯片里，
but here I have two dimensional data,
不过我这里有两维数据，
so I have z1 and z2 as
Z1和Z2做为
the two components of the data.
数据的两个组件。
Now, let me just make sure
现在，让我确定一下
that these figures make sense. So
这些数字的意义。所以
let me just reshow these exact
让我的再现这些精确的
three figures again but with 3D plots.
三维图。
So the process we went through was that
所以过程我们经历的是
shown in the lab is the optimal
在实验室证明是最优的
data set, in the middle the
数据集，在中间
data set projects on the 2D,
数据集项目对应二维，
and on the right the 2D
和右边的2D
data sets with z1 and z2 as the axis.
Z1和Z2为轴的数据集，
Let's look at them a little
让我们看他们再深入一点。
bit further. Here's my original
这是我的原始
data set, shown on the
数据集，显示在
left, and so I had started
左变，所以我开始
off with a 3D point
和一个三维点
cloud like so, where the
像云一样，在那里
axis are labeled x1,
轴标记为X1，
x2, x3, and so there's a 3D
X2，X3，所以这是一个三维
point but most of the data,
点，但多数数据，
maybe roughly lies on some,
也许大约位于，
you know, not too far from some 2D plain.
你知道，不会太远离二维平面。
So, what we can
所以，我们可以
do is take this data and here's my middle figure.
做的是把这个数据，这是我的中间图。
I'm going to project it onto 2D.
我将它投影到二维。
So, I've projected this data so
所以，我预计这一数据
that all of it now lies on this 2D surface.
，这一切点都在这个2D表面。
As you can see all the data
你可以看到所有的数据
lies on a plane, 'cause we've
在是一个平面，因为我们
projected everything onto a
投射到的一切到一个
plane, and so what this means is that
平面，所以这意味着
now I need only two numbers,
现在我只需要两个数，
z1 and z2, to represent
Z1和Z2，代表
the location of point on the plane.
点在的平面上的位置。
And so that's the process that
这样的过程
we can go through to reduce our
我们可以通过减少我们的
data from three dimensional to
数据从三维到
two dimensional. So that's
二维。这样的
dimensionality reduction and how
降维及
we can use it to compress our data.
我们可以用它来压缩数据。
And as we'll see
正如我们所看到的，
later this will allow us to
最后，这将使我们能够
make some of our learning algorithms
使我们的一些学习算法
run much later as well, but
运行也较晚，但
we'll get to that only in a later video.
我们会在以后的视频提到它。